Hello hello everyone how are you all I am
your own personal advisor Amit Raj Sharma and
you are watching Yudh Real today's video
credit goes to Mr Rahul Pathak
Mr Rahul Pathak has commented in the comment section of the video of Childs Future Ashok Plant of Aditya Birla Sun
Life Insurance Company Limited
saying that he
wants this video of SP Plan thank you very much
friend Pathak for this comment
now because every video on the channel
comes according to your suggestions, comments and questions so you should like the video by clicking on the like button
and
subscribe to the channel by clicking on the subscribe written in red color just below the video turn on all notification bells so that
whenever the sentence on the media
is according to the question and comment you
get it at the right time and you will not get to know so
now without wasting time let us understand the details of Short Saving Plan of Aditya Birla Sun
Life Insurance Company Limited
this is Plan
19 Land Not Participating Individual
Life Insurance Policy means that it is such a
plan in which companies will
not invest in the market on premium  It is not
participating, hence the return will be
guaranteed. You will know that
you get two types of options in the plan. Single
life means you will take cover for yourself. Joint life
means that you will be
able to cover your spouse along with yourself under the scheme.
20% of the sum which you will consider as basic for yourself will be the
cover amount around you. Now let's talk about the
life insurance criteria. If the child's
age is more than 30 days, then you will be
able to take this plan for the child, otherwise the
maximum age limit is up to 65 years.
In case of joint life, the entries which are limited are from 18
years to 50 years.
You get two options for premium payment, the first
is single life and the second is limited life. Single life
means you know that you have to pay the premium one time.
If you take the limited life
option, then the premium
payment option you get is from five years to
12 years. After that comes the
policy term, if you opt for single life, then you will
get the option of policy term from five years to 20 years. If you have
taken the premium payment option on limited life, then  The
option of power system which you will
get between 10 years to 35 years, maximum up to 35 years will be available. Okay, now let's
come to the minimum premium amount
limit. If you have to choose the single option, then you will have to pay a
minimum premium of Rs 1 lakh as
basic premium, only then you will be able to take this plan.
If we take the premium payment for 5 years,
then we will have to pay Rs 20 thousand annually,
then we will get the premium. Similarly, for the
premium paying term option of 12 years,
if you make a premium payment of Rs 3000 for six years, 10 years or 12 years, then you will have to make the
entry of spoon dry ginger which depends on the amount. The
entries will be made according to this explanation. You will understand the comment accordingly.
For example, the
screenshot of the skin is above. If you have
taken the single option, then two options are
available in it. What is there in the first option? In option A, in the
half premium that you are paying, you will make a
horse of Rs 1.25, your government will come out.
What will happen to the option that you are
paying on the premium, now you
will make a * in it.  The premium you pay on
single will be 10 times that. If you have
taken an option on limited and you use option number one in it, then
what will happen is that your
advised premium will now be increased by 11 times, that is,
11 times. In option two, the
support you have in the industry, now these factors that I have
told you, 11 times, ten times, one and a quarter times, will keep increasing or
decreasing according
to the size. Okay, so it will
vary on that basis. I have given the overall wait here, that is, I have
given an idea. Now when it comes to the
benefit, the first thing is that there will be a
death benefit here. If you are taking a single option
and the body system is
less than 25 years old or if it happens before 25 years,
then understand that on the short term date, you will get the
nut loyalty addition,
but if the date of life should be
after 25 years, it means that the
child in your audit is more than 10 years old,
then in such a case, the one which was present before or the
guaranteed maturity benefit which is higher among the two will be
added to it, the
quality addition which  The amount will be given to the
snake. Now the matter comes to the clarification that
what is it, in case of single premium, whatever will be
your respect and if you do not take the plan, that will be
your respect short term date, but
if you have taken the option of your limit premium, then
your basic spoon dry ginger which we are
leaving the society or the premium which you have offered on the
10th date of birth,
150 percent of that, whichever is higher, will be
your respect awards death. Now the matter
of note here means this important
point that if you want that the nominee should get the
death benefit in installments, that too with a
period of 5 years, in annual or monthly mode
as you wish, then you can do this
in this plan and the ratio in this will be
if you have chosen annual mode, then
21.83 eight percent of the total health benefits amount will be given annually, that is,
its total health benefit
amount. Shukra will see the answer in this way
that how much will be the total death benefit, that will be
102 of the total death benefit.  9.19 One percent
annual rate has been taken, if the minister has taken the rate then it will be
available at the rate of 1.8 57 percent in monthly mode
and the total saver mode will be settled, meaning you will get
dormant in the installment of the total cost, you will
get 11.45 percent of the death benefit, so you
can also use such installment mode and
whichever option you choose, you will
not be able to change it in this plan later, then keep in
mind that now when it comes to maturity
benefit, the maturity benefit
is simple, in this along with your guaranteed maturity
benefit, you will get your loyalty addition, the
total corpus which will be accumulated,
you will get that and when you withdraw, so right now what is the
guaranteed maturity benefit, it will be
a fixed percentage of the premium you have paid, the
rate of percentage depends on the premium
payment question and your age, now the loyalty
addition has been done, when your premium payment is
completed, then the premium at the rate of a fixed percentage  The
percentage pain that will be applied on top of what you have presented
and the tender maturity will keep getting paid, which means it will keep getting
paid in the plan itself. Now
see, if you take this plan and opt for
your limited par option in it, then the social
mode on the chilli will be more accurate, that is, the
guaranteed maturity benefit that will accrue will
increase. If you have
taken option number two with limited par, which I
told you a while ago, if you
watched the video carefully, you will remember
how much the guaranteed maturity
benefit will increase. If we pay the premium for 5 to 8 years, then it will become
4% extra, which
means we will get
4% increase of the guaranteed maturity amount. The premium payment for 9 to 10
years will
increase at the rate of five percent, that is,
suppose the guaranteed maturity benefit is ₹1000000, then
five percent amount will be
added to it. If the premium payment term is 11 or 2, then
seven percent amount of the guaranteed maturity benefit will be
added to it and you will get it if you  If you have
taken option number two along with the limited option, then now comes the matter of loyalty
addition. If you have taken the limited option
and have taken the joint life option, because the
joint life option will be available to you along with the limited option.
If you are between 18 to 50 years,
which is the age limit, then the
minimum rate is 4.80 percent and the
maximum rate is 11.85 percent. So,
if you pay a premium of Rs. 10 lakh, then you will
get at least a loyalty addition at the rate of 4.8 percent till the
maturity. But if you have taken the single life
option and have taken the premium payment option on limited, then the
rate of loyalty addition will depend on your age. If you are between
50 years to 60 years, then
you will get at least a loyalty addition at the rate of 6.90 percent. The
loyalty addition plan will be applicable for the period
from 514 to
65 years. Loyalty addition will be applicable every year after the
premium is paid from 564
to 65 years.  Along with this,
loyalty addition will keep accruing at the rate of 5.30 percent.
If the age in the plan is from 18 years to 65 years, then loyalty
addition mode will keep getting at the rate of 1.10 percent. The
maximum percentage
which you are getting on your skin on the dry skin side,
if you have
taken the option on single for premium, then in
such a case the
rate of loyalty addition will remain between 1.15 to 10.75 percent
because it will
depend on what the entries are and
it will start when your first policy
ends, the second policy will start getting accrued
from then and will
get it till maturity. Now suppose
you have taken the option on limited, single life
means limited premium payment Amavasya
single life, here we are taking cover of
Shri Maa, her age is 30 years, the
premium payment player is six years old, the one who has tested
positive is 12 years old and the food which
Prem is doing here is basic,
tax is not included in this.
In such a situation, what will be possible for them will be Rs 13 lakh
10 thousand, the total premium which will be
paid in six years will be of Rs 6 lakh
and the guaranteed maturity benefit which you will get, you can also check it by assuming that the
guaranteed is written will be an
amount above Rs 10 lakh,
this is the screenshot, I have used it
on the premium calculator and website,
from which you get the cover,
you can also check it on that, now suppose on
single, that is, you are taking single premium option,
Mr. is Hawaii, his age is 40
years and he is taking single life cover, that is, he is living for
himself and he wants that the
lump sum basic premium of Rs 6 lakh should be
packed here, so in such a situation, the
spoon fennel factor will be 1.35, assuming here that
1.35 times the premium of Rs 6 lakh, that is,
his respect of Rs 8 lakh 10 thousand will be left
here, now the
character of guaranteed maturity, let us
assume here the per power of 73.8, is its
full  You will get the chapter on the Telegram channel.
Now you know that the
loyalty
addition will be applied on the total premium paid. We are assuming it to be 10.15
percent and there is a single option, so when the second
year is completed, this loyalty addition will
start appearing. Now, here I am
assuming the policy term to be 15 years. Now
see, the loyalty addition will
start accruing from the completion of the second year, which means it will
not be available for one year, the rest will be available till maturity. So,
here we
can assume the loyalty addition to be 14 years. In such a situation,
we already know the loyalty addition rate, so
what will be the total roti addition benefit in 14 years? If we
subtract 10.15 percent of Chhaila and add Chaube to it, then it will become
852684. If we
know about the guaranteed maturity sector, then
what will be the guaranteed maturity benefit? If
we subtract 73.8 percent of Chhaila, then it will be
₹442001 100  If we add these two then the
total maturity
benefit can be obtained at Rs. 95400. Now the video is getting long
so we will divide it into 2 parts.
In the next lesson we will talk about
joint life benefit with an example. With the
example we will understand
all its benefits along with the electrician. We will understand
how to calculate the surrender value. We will
understand
how to calculate the reduction victim. We will understand
what will be the loan amount and how much interest will be charged on it.
We will also tell you this.